Preliminary Guide to the Short Run Publications, 1884-2016 RG0120
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Short Run Student and University Publications
1884-2016
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
RG0120
10.75 Linear Feet
This collection contains old publications from The George Washington University offices and student groups that are no longer in publication. Most of these files only contain a few issues and are potentially incomplete runs. The publications range in date from 1884 to 2016.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
The collection was accessioned into the collection in 2001, but the provenance is unknown.
Historical or Biographical Note
A portion of this collection was part of a backlog that has an unknown provenance. In 2001, the items were accessioned into the collection within its own record group to contain University and student organization publications that are no longer published.
Arrangement
Organized into one series.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection contains publications from The George Washington University offices and student groups that are no longer being published. They range in date from 1884 to 2016. Most of these files only contain a few issues and are potentially incomplete runs.
Student organizations; Student publications; Short Run publications; Publications; Foggy Bottom (Washington, D.C.); Washington (D.C.); George Washington University
- Short run publications, 1901-2016; Series 1; 10.75 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains old publications from University offices and student groups that are no longer being published. They range in date from 1884 to 2005.
  Formerly ACC#999
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Ace Magazine, 2014; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Alumni Hatchet, 1927-1931; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alumni News, 1924-1927; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alumni Publications - School of Business and Public Management - "Insight" newsletter, 1988-1992; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alumni Publications - School of Education Newsletter, 1991-1993; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Amicus Curiae, 1952-1965; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Association of University Professors Newsletter, GWU chapter, 1995-1996; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Angioscope, 1989-1990; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Art Department Newsletter, 1980-1984; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Articles from the School of Government Business and International Affairs, 1946-1961; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bank On DC, 2014 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - The Big To Do, 1990; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The Big To Do, 1991-1993; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Big To Do, 1994; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bioscience "Capsule", 1964 May 15 - 1969 May 26; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - The Buff and The Blue, 1990-1990; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - The Buff and The Blue, 1991; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - The Buff and The Blue, 1992; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - The Career Line, 1976 October- 1981 October; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Cast Newsletter - University Theater, 1983; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Center for Academic and Administrative Computing bulletin, 1981-1982; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Centerfold, 1976; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - The Center Piece, 1975 February 25; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Circle, 1975-1977; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Clio's Chronicle, 1980 January; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - College of General Studies Evening Times, 1970-1974; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - College of General Studies Evening Times, 1975-1980; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - College News, 1913; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - The Colonial Cadet, 1954-1961; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Colonial Chronicles, 1988-1992; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Colonial Review, 1930 November 19; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Colonial Review, 1930 December 19; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Colonial Review, 1931 January 21; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Colonial Review, 1931 February 18; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Colonial Review, 1931 March 18; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Colonial Review, 1931 April 22; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Colonial Review, 1931 May 27; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Colonial Review, 1950; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Colonial Weekly, 2003; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Colonial Wig, 1928-1929; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Columbian - GWU Law School Association Bulletin, 1925-1936; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - The Columbian, 1923; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - The Columbian College Advisor, 1976 December - !979 March; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Columbian University Magazine, 1901 June; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Commission on Undergraduate Education on Biological Science, 1965-1972; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Computer Center News, 1970-1984; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Confidential - From Washington, 1942-1950; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - The Courier, 1949; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - The Courier, 1950; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - The Courier, 1951; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - The Courier, 1952; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - The Courier, 1953; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - The Courier, 1954; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - The Courier, 1955; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - The Courier, 1956; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - The Courier, 1958; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - The Courier, 1959; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - The Courier, 1960; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - The Courier, 1961; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - The Courier, 1962; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - The Courier, 1963; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - The Courier, 1964; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Current, 1982-1983; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Current, 1984-1985; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Current, 1987-1988; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Department of Medicine Newsletter, 1979-1981; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Department of Chemistry Newsletter, 1980-1982; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Education Times, 1980 January 28- 1980 September 15; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Education Times, 1980 September 29 - 1981 January 12; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Education Times, 1981 January 19 - 1981 May 11; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Education Times, 1981 May 18 - 1981 September 8; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Electronic Engineering and Computing Science News, 1989-1991; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Encore Newsletter, 1988; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Federal Accountant, 1965; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Federalist, 1954-1957; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Federalist, 1958-1963; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Financial Planning Newsletter, 1974-1988; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Forecast SBPM Undergraduate Programs, 1990-1993; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Friday, 1978; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - The Globe, 2012-2013; Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - The Globe, 2014; Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - The Globe, 2015; Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - The Globe, 2016; Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - GW Calendar, 1964-1968; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - GW Colonial, 1987; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - GW Consult, 1965; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - GW Democrat, 1965; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - GW Engineering News, 1966, 1968; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - GW Focus for Parents, 1976-1982; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - GW Interfraternity Life, 1940-; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - GW International, 1987-1993; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - GW Journal, 1983-1992; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - GW Law Association Newsletter, 1975-1986; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - GW Minute publication, 03/1999-09/2009 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    General note
    This folder includes the newsletter, "GW Minute", which is produced by the Office of Government, International and Corporate Affairs. This publication primarily concerns community relations and involvement. This newsletter ranges in date from March 1999- September 2005.
  - GW Music, 1981-1982; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - GW News, 1968-1971; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - GW Patriot publication, 03/2003-03/2005 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    This folder includes the student run publication "GW Patriot", which is a monthly conservative journal that offers commentary on politics and culture at George Washington University. This newsletter ranges in date from March 2003- March 2005.
  - GW Review, 1983-2002; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - GW Sequent, 1982-=1983; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - GW Sequent, 1983-1986; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - GW Times, 1972-1983; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - GW Times, 1987-1989; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - GW Tribune, 1988; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - GW Weekly Calander, 1987-1989; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - GW Women's Studies Newsletter, 1977-1979; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - GWU Access, 1978-1981; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - GWU Debate League Handbooks, 1937-1941; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - GWU Debate League Handbooks, 1937-1941; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - GWU Gazette, 1957; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - GWU Library Staff Notes, 1970-1973; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - GWU Medical Center, 1981-1984; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - GWUMC in the News, 1974-1985; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Greensheets GWU Hospital, 1978-1991; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Grind, Jan. 1947; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Happenings, 1975; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Harbinger, 1974-1976; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Hatchet Encounter, 1968; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Health Link, 1989-1990; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Health News, 1999; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Helicon, 1941; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 11a)
  - History Department publications "Washington Past", undated; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 11b)
  - Hydrobiology Newsletter, 1964-1968; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Information Interface, 1976-1979; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Information Interface, 1980-1982; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Information Interface, 1983-1989; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Inside, 1976; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Institute of Law and Aging newsletter, 1976-1978; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - The InterMediary, 1968-1973; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 18a)
  - International Services Newsletter, 1983-1985; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 18b)
  - International Student Advisory Newsletter, 1972-1983; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - International Student Advisory Newsletter, 1972-1983; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Job Opportunities Bulletin, 1979-1983; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Journal of Religious Concern, 1973-1974; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Kaleidoscope, 1986-1990; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Lash, 1926; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Law Alumni News, 1962-1973; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Maedenheap, 1985; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Marvin 424 - The Bull, 1980-1981; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Maternal and Child Health Exchange, 1970-1972; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Matrix, 1965-1968; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Medical News of GWU, 1958-1959; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Mid-East Weekly Perspective, 1979 October 12; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Mortar Board Forum, 1984; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - MusEd NEWS, 1984-1989; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 5a)
  - The New Hamburgh Visitor, 1964; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 5b)
  - NEWS Law Alumni Association, 1984-1989; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 5c)
  - News from the Women's Studies Progam, 1979; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - News Releases GWU Medical Center, 1967-1982; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - news... news.. news... from Grad. Prog. in Historic Preservation, 1978; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Newsletter of the Doctoral SA, 1971-1972; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - O.S.A.-Organization for Student Action, 1958; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Observer, 1991-1992; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - On the Line, Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Other Side / Broadside, 1965; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Out Front, 1970 February 15; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Pachyderm, 1971; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Panamerican Voice, 1988-1989; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Pendulum, 1924; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Percolator, 1959; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Petticoat, 1923-1931; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Pharmacy Newsletter, 1971-1983; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Plannerisms, 1977-1990; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Potomac, Fall 1962; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - The Potomac Breeze, 1924; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Protest This, 1997; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Quid Novi - What's New, 1974/75, 1985/86; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Rag, 1980-1981; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - The Razzberry, 1922 February 2- 1933 February 2; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Research Currents, 1970-1984; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Research Currents, 1970-1984; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Research Support Times, 1986-1988; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 28a)
  - Safety and Security, Office of Campus Police - Pride in Protection and Service, 1997-1999; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 28b)
  - Scope, 1983; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Scope of the GWU Hospital, 1951-1970; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Sour Grapes, 1923 December 12; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Scope - school of medicine, Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Spectator, 1884 October-1886 May; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Student's Minaret, 1990 Spring; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Student's Russian Monthly, 1960 January; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Summer School Record, 1944-1952, 1961-1964; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Surveyor, 1947 Winter; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Synergy publication, 2001-2003 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    This folder includes the publication "Synergy", which is a magazine produced by the School of Engineering and Applied Science. Materials range in date from 2001- 2003.
  - Telecommunications News, 1989; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Transition, 1965; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - The University Hatchet- Alumni Edition, 1931 November; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Vernacular Architecture, 1979; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Verse publication, 2004-2005 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    This folder includes four issues of the student run magazine, "Verse", which is an entertainment and fashion magazine aimed at George Washington University students. This publication ranges in date from February 2004- April 2005.
  - Vital Signs, 1977 - 1984; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - The Voice (Mt. Vernon Campus), 1999-2001; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - The W.A.S. Post, 1980-1981; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Washington Insider, 1979-1980; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - What's Happening, 1971-1979; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - What's Happening, 1979-1981; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - What's Up George?, 1985 January-1985 June; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Wig, Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Womanspace Newsletter, 1975-1977; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Women's Issues Now (WIN), 1980; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - WSPPC News, 1980; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 15)